## PRAJAKTA DILIP LIMJE.

Cambridge, ON | (226) 978-1353 | github.com/Praj-akta | prajaktalimje13@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/plimje

### **OBJECTIVE**

Creative frontend web developer offering 3 year of experience providing high impact web solutions for diverse industry organizations. Skilled in designing, development and testing multiple web-based applications incorporating multiple technologies. Aspiring to combine broad background with strong technical skills to excel as frontend web developer.

#### **EDUCATION**

Conestoga College

Post-Graduation in Web Development GPA: 3.8

Mumbai University, Saraswati College of Engineering

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering

Waterloo, ON

Jan 2022 - April 2023

Maharashtra, India May 2014 - May 2018

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: JavaScript, React JS, React Hooks, React Native, Angular JS(1.6), Express JS, Node JS

Web Development: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, React Styled Components.

Database: MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Stripe, MariaDB.

Tools and Packages: GIT, MS Office, JIRA, Slack, Visual Studio

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Infojini. Mumbai, India

React JS Web Developer (Team Size: 6)

May 2019 - October 2022

- Developed websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from wireframe through deployment.
- Planned development as per Standardized output through a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy. Enhanced UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Collaborated with product team members for feature gathering and sprint planning.
- Developed Unit and Load test cases to improve application architecture, maintainability, and scalability.
  Designed an interactive, dynamic HR portal and Veteran websites using HTML, CSS with modern JavaScript frameworks as React, Angular and React Native for better experience.

### **GVK**, Mumbai International Airport.

Mumbai, India

Web Developer Intern (Team Size: 10)

August 2018 - May 2019

- Worked with customers for requirement gathering and understand the scope of the project. Conducted research, gathered information from multiple sources and presented results.
- Designed user friendly web pages using HTML, CSS and REACT JS.
- Performed load, unit testing and provided scaling parameters to infra team
- Prioritized and accomplished multiple tasks within established timeframes.

### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

### Amazon Clone: (HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, React JS, Redux, Node JS, Firebase, Stripe)

- Cloned Amazon website, using HTML, CSS/SCSS, React JS, Redux, Firebase and Stripe, Express JS.
- Website has ability to add product or remove product from the cart, order history is maintained under 'Return & orders' section.
- Leveraged Firebase for storing the user's data (email id and password) and orders history of user. Used Stripe for authentication and authorization of payments
- Node JS, Redux and React JS for hosting the payment method, for global storage and data retrieval, for single page application respectively.

### Drive Test Application: (HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, React JS, Node JS, MongoDB)

- Developed a website for G1/G2 Drive Test application online, where users can book an appointment or schedule their dates for driving.
- Website is designed using HTML/CSS, Bootstrap and the languages used for frontend is React JS. For Backend, Node JS and MongoDB is used for storing the user's data.

# Employee Management System: (HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, React JS, React Hooks, Node JS, MongoDB)

- Developed an employee management system, where employee's data can be created, updated, and deleted by performing CRUD operations.
- Created functional components using React hooks, also MongoDB is used for data Storage. API integration is done

using Fetch API calls.

• Website has been developed and designed using HTML/CSS, Bootstrap and React JS.

## Food Mobile Application: (Flutter iOS, Firebase, Android Studio)

- Developed a food application using flutter. This application displays the slider of the popular food items where the list of new dishes has been displayed.
- Data has been displayed using Firebase. Using Http API call, the data is fetched.

## Netflix Clone: (HTML/CSS, Tailwind CSS, React JS, Redux, Firebase, Axios)

- Cloned Netflix website, using HTML/CSS, Tailwind CSS, React Hooks, Redux, Firebase, Axios.
- Website has ability to create an account or sign in with existing credentials, also adding favorites movies to "My List" option.
- Used Firebase for storing the user's data (email id and password). Fetched data through TDMB (online Movie's API) axios.